Last night, on the stretch of road between Bogachevo station and the village of Stupino, Soviet planes bombed a convoy of trucks transporting supplies. While the enemies are gathering up the surviving cargo, you can move in and take it yourselves.
Our planes shot up a truck convoy on the road last night. They were probably carrying something valuable, like supplies or ammo for the garrison. Well, whatever it is, we can find a better use for it.
The Germans shot down a Soviet plane flying night reconnaissance. The pilot bailed out and landed somewhere in the forest. We can go look for him.
Sounds of battle came from the Soviet front line during the night. Some townsfolk wanted to get their hands on weapons and bumped into a Fascist patrol. We should take a look at the site.
Where are your guardians?
Who's the boss now?
When will daddy come back?
Screw this.
Come on, partisans, I dare you!
You’re done for!
Got to check!
NEED TO UNEQUIP
Immediately report all suspicious activity to your local authorities, military command or members of the Ordnungsdienst.
Eh, a corpse, Gotta search the pockets.
Hah! Gotcha!
SQUAD INVENTORY
SQUAD STASH
PRIMARY EVENTS
OSOAVIAKhIM—a paramilitary volunteer organization, dedicated to the preparation of the reserves for the armed forces. Up to 80% of the draftees of the Red Army had badges of the organization. More than 7.2 million OSOAVIAKhIM members joined the army, the militia and the partisans during the first months of war.
CONFIRM
CANCEL
SKILL POINTS:
Anesthetic
Painkillers
Painkillers and things for healing in battlefield. Restores partisan health.
Manhunt
Deception
Deceit
Defense of Steel
Processed wood.
Investigate the crash site
Tutorial battle mission
Tutorial stealth mission
Coming around!
Object
The object will be locked. It will become available after repairs.
Container looting
Search Biermeier's office
Common
A regular handkerchief. Sanek's mom put it in his pocket the last time he saw her.
Vegetables
Clothes
Clothes make you feel warm and look pretty.
Spray cologne
Odessa has been holding against the Fascist hordes for more than a month now. The city is being rapidly evacuated.
One of the lists
One down! 
Ambush is one of the most important tools of the partisan struggle. Small groups of 6-10 fighters take positions along the enemy route using trees, ditches and bushes for cover. Camouflage your position well: The enemy must not detect you. Find a place that allows you a wide arc of fire.
I'm mom's only helper.
One of our main goals is to disrupt the enemy's supply chain by sabotaging the railway. A bridge collapse will delay railroad traffic and make a real contribution to our victory.
I've only got one chicken left.
Partisans are our only hope.
Forest lake
Yikes!
I'm so scared!
Yikes! A dead man.
Uh-oh! What's this?
There go some strangers
There go some strangers.
The occupants are actively spreading their propaganda, besmirching the Soviet government and using lies to attract people to their cause.
Olga was teaching Valentina some hand-to-hand combat, which resulted in a minor injury to the pupil.
He didn't die his own death. 
They shot all the Germans!
They should be around.
They're searching for us!
They have no mercy.
Whoa, what's that? 
Danger! 
Quick reaction
Operational HQ
It didn't go as planned. The enemy fought back. We had to retreat into the woods.
The operation was successful. We took the enemy by surprise.
Description
"Eiserne Ration" field rations description
Listen to the voice of reason! Stop the senseless bloodshed! Stick your bayonets into the ground!
Experience
Partisans experience +300
Experience: 
Experienced partisan
Experienced Strategist
Experienced surgeons can sew severed limbs. The most experienced can even sew them on the right places.
They'll be hanging people again.
There's war again...
Bad guys are fighting again.
Not crawling under bushes again!
Weapon workshop
Gun oil
Melee weapon. Used for stealth kills.
Rescue Belozerova
Rescue Comrade Zorin
Rescue Comrade Fetisov
Liberate the first khutor
Rescue the townsfolk
Liberate the second khutor
Liberate the third khutor
Studying the basics of partisan warfare increases your chances of success in missions and allows other inhabitants of the camp to take part in them.
Heavy autumn rain washed out some roads. A German truck with food taken from the townsfolk has stalled in the mud. It looks like easy prey.
Heavy autumn rain washed out some roads. A German truck with medical equipment has stalled in the mud. It looks like easy prey.
Heavy autumn rain washed out some roads. A German truck carrying weapons from a captured detachment has stalled in the mud. It looks like easy prey.
In the fall of 1941, 10 year old Valya Kotyk performed his first feat.