There's so much blood!
Haemostatic powder
Goddamned bloodsuckers! They're taking what little we have left.
Some locations may be equipped with sirens: If activated, a siren will raise an alarm in a large area.
The Crimea is completely under Fascist control. Or so the Fascists think: The peninsula is a perfect environment for partisan activities.
Who is your contact?
Those who permit the brigands to act, are no better than brigands themselves!
Who threw this?
No one has yet returned after being arrested and taken to prison.
Who's there? 
Who's so cheeky?
They think they got themselves a full pardon?
Where are all the pretty gals?
Alexander Ivanovich Kuzmin  
Kuzmin, Alexander Ivanovich. Age: 14. Local. Before the war, studied at school. Member of the Pioneer organization. Lost both parents to the Fascists. He lives in the forest with Trofim and dreams about avenging his family.
Kulagin
Kulagin has heard from his acquaintances that every person in town is forced to work for the occupants. Any kinds of sabotage lead to immediate execution. The people are fleeing; the town's population has shrunk considerably.
A Little Culture
Smoking is very bad for your health. Don't smoke.
I want a smoke.
Henhouse
Makeshift grenade
Makeshift mine
Kitchen
I'm hungry.
LEGEND
PERSONAL
LMB - start action (set up actions in tactical pause)
LMB+Shift - set up a sequence of actions
Kerosene lamp
Lamp that works on kerosene. They're used everywhere.
Legendary
Logging site
Sawmill
Sawmill 
Healing
Treatment
Recovering from injuries received during missions.
Healing complete
Treat
False partisan
Liar!
The lying German leaflets are down! They won't mislead people any longer.
Rain, fog, snowfall
Kill the propagandist
Eliminate mayor
Eliminate all village heads
Kill the officer
Eliminate the village head
We replaced the propagandists' leaflets with our own. The townsfolk now know that the partisans are close by.
I just hope they won't start shooting.
I just hope my kids will be okay.
Dodger I
Dodger II
Down!
Reduce Max Range
A shovel is a great tool for close combat. It can protect you against your enemy's blows; it can deflect bayonet attacks; and its sharp edges make it a serious cutting weapon. A shovel is especially valuable during melee in tight spaces.
Losinoe lake
I'd rather stay inside.
Every enemy in the game has a cone of vision. Move your cursor to an enemy and press RMB to see it. Keep out of the cone and don't be caught!
No matter what
Leave them folks be!
M30 Luftwaffe
OUT OF BULLETS
MG – 34
MEDICAL DUGOUT
MENU
MONTH
MISSION
MISSION COMPLETED
MISSION FAILED
MODIFIERS
SQUAD MORALE
MP – 40
Max distance
Max. distance
Maximum morale
Vastly increases the amount of HP recovered when using medkits.
Greatly increased speed of killing any enemy while in stealth. Greatly increased chance of winning melee fights.
Vastly increased chance to hit using rifles.
Vastly increased chance to hit using SMGs.
Vastly increased chance to hit using pistols.
Vastly increased chance to hit using heavy machine guns and stationary weapons.
Vastly increased chance to hit using shotguns.
Maximum character defense bonus while sprinting.
Maximum chance to hit during ambush mode [Y].
A squad can have 1-4 partisans based on the selected mission.
Max Damage
Mom tells me to stay home, but I want to go out.
Mom is always crying. I feel sorry for her.
Mom says granny will never come back.
Mommy is at work. It's scary to be alone.
Mommy, I'm scared.
Mommy!
Oh dear!
They killed my mom and dad.
Disguise
I'm out of slugs.
Workshop  
Workshop 