Hurray! It's the partisans!
storm
Complexity level
Complexity level: {difficulty}
Wounded partisans can die if they don't get treatment in time. Saving during missions is blocked. Tactical mode doesn't slow time.
Enemy and partisan health is very low. Every combat is a serious challenge. Dogs are very dangerous.
The harvest is rotting out there.
Damage
Farmstead
Reinforced spring
Reinforce the patrols!
Moves faster while using the Evasion roll ability
Did my family have a chance to evacuate?
Make it before the SS squad arrives
Success
Fatigue
Plant explosives
We chose not to set up an ambush. We had bigger fish to fry.
Eliminate locomotive brigade
We ambushed the cart and liberated the food. We can have a hearty meal tonight.
The next morning, we found a hare in the trap hole.
The next morning, we found elk traces near the base. We could try to track it down.
Ugh, blasted scum!
The fish stew is very good.
Taking care of your personal weapon is what distinguishes a civilized person from a Neanderthal.
Oof... It was a big bang!
Accounting and Control
I'd walk off into the woods and join the partisans if I didn't have to feed my family.
I'd walk off into the woods and join the partisans if I didn't have to feed my kids.
The Fascists have surrounded Sevastopol and the main base of the Black Sea Fleet. The city is mounting a valiant defense.
The Fascists unload their grain at the local mill. Vasily Gavrilovich thinks that the miller is a good person. We should visit the mill and see if he can store some flour for us.
The Fascists are hunting down the fugitives.
The Fascists are using P.O.W.'s at the sawmill. The locals say they treat them brutally. We need to help them escape—and sabotage their equipment while we're at it.
The Fascists are forcing people into the fields to harvest whatever is left out there. The crops will be sent to the front. We can't hijack the food train, but we can poison the provisions ready for shipment.
The Fascists set an ambush in the village. We spotted it in time and managed to escape. We didn't get any information.
The Fascists set an ambush in the village. We barely escaped.
They treat us like slaves.
The Fascists are looking for partisans.
Fascists have shut down almost every school in the district. The ones remaining are teaching just four classes—as much as the Russian people need to know, according to their "new masters".
The Fascists are fixing an old fortress that used to be a prison long ago. People are saying they are forcing the prisoners of war to do this—building their own future holding cells.
The Fascists are conducting public executions, using every excuse imaginable. Every day someone gets killed.
Fetisov
Nikolay Alexandrovich Fetisov
Fetisov, Nikolay Alexandrovich. Age: 24. Born in Leningrad into a worker's family. Decathlete. Student of Lesgaft University of Sport and Health. Joined the army under the Komsomol draft call in the first week of war. He was a sergeant in Captain Zorin's company.
Fetisov managed to hurt his hand while fixing the roof. It'll show him to watch where the hammer falls.
Fetisov shoots everyone within range of the ability cone. Requires an SMG.
Fomin
German flashlight
German film camera. Manufactured by Voigtlander since 1936.
Voigtlander camera
A picture of Fetisov's fiancée. The words "I'll wait for you. Nastya" are written in neat handwriting on the back.
Photograph
Photograph: "PzKpfw IV"
Photograph: "Soviet Partisan Unit"
Photograph: "The Crew at Muster"
Film
The Fascists are really annoyed. I shouldn't get in their way.
We're the same as lice to the Germans.
The Fascists steal everything they can get.
Ew, one of my blisters burst.
Biermeier is in charge of the foragers.
Whew, that was nothing.
Kharkiv, an important industrial center and railway hub, has fallen to the Germans after a month of intense battles. Most large factories were already evacuated, and the rest were destroyed, so they wouldn't fall into the enemy's hands.
Surgeon kit
Bread
Chloroform I
Chloroform II
There are rumors that Commandant Mellenberg is planning to implement even more brutal counter-partisan measures. What does that bastard have in mind?
Craft and Supply
Utility buildings that will help the partisans avoid starvation.
Household
It's getting cold.
Mining the roads can also give good results. Place mines at several different spots and camouflage them as best as you can, then hide so that you won't be harmed by the explosion yourself. Use every weapon in your arsenal to deal with whatever enemies remain after an encounter with your mines. Road mining is best performed during the night hours, just before dawn.
Skilled doctor
I'm glad my old man isn't alive to see this.
Glad it wasn't me.
Let everything be fine.
Whether she likes it or not, she will be mine.
God bless you.
Keep it out of reach of children.
Ugh, bloody partisans! I have to stick around because of them.
Bloody partisans.
Khutor 
I’ve been stuck here all day without any grub.
Mission goal
Personal mission goal
Side mission goal
The Center is planning an air strike on Krasnoselskaya station to destroy the cannon known as Slender Bertha. But first we must sneak into the station for a little sabotage.
Focus camera on partisan after loading
D-damn boots... I got blisters all over my feet!
Tea is good at quenching thirst—and generally good for your health.
1st-grade Indian tea
Payback Time
Some food has been spoiled as a result of the recent high humidity levels.
Wristwatch
What if the partisans attack?
They just won't let it go.
What else is there?
Delicious rations are better.
German trains carrying soldiers and vehicles are passing through Bogachevo. We should do something about it.