Find archives
Find some explosives
Find the red banner at the warehouse 
Find aerial photography materials
Find the equipment
Find all forest caches
Finally, it's over.
I've finally achieved something.
We'll smoke the meat and store it.
The raid
An ambush with the purpose of obtaining enemy equipment and supplies should be particularly quiet, with as little gunfire and explosions as possible. Small-caliber rifles should be used, if available: Their report is notably quiet, while they still allow you to incapacitate guards and drivers to finish them off with close-combat weaponry later.
We only need to last till winter, when the Germans will surely freeze.
We managed to build a trap from whatever was available.
We managed to create some painkillers from whatever was available.
Attack from an ambush
I wish I could send my sweetheart a letter and tell him I'm no good without him!
Hard
Task 
Unseen and Untouched
We're gonna get killed!
We Weren't There
We've been robbed three times already.
Configurações
Graphic settings were changed. Do you want to apply them?
Onwards to a new day
Nastya jumped in bed with an officer! Isn't she a whore?
Valentin was initially tasked with collecting weapons and ammunition in German-occupied territories, along with the distribution of propagandist leaflets.
His first combat mission was a hard one. An officer of the Feldgendarmerie (German military police) was to drive in his car down the motorway from Shepetovka to Slavuta. At a set time Valya and his friends took positions in the bushes by the road. Soon the sound of the engine reached their ears. When the Fascist car was passing the boys' positions, Valya Kotyk stood up and threw a grenade, killing the commanding officer.
Heavy rains have turned the roads into mud. The Germans are stuck on their way to Moscow. It's time to push back!
Start
Start 
Begin work on assigned tasks
Restart
Begin mission
Start new day
They burned down our house.
Our man down.
Our army ran like hell.
Our fighter planes shot down an enemy aircraft. It landed in the woods over by the lake, where we hunt. If he was a scout, he was probably taking pictures. We're going to search the crash site and see what he got on film.
What the hell is wrong with them?
Our comrades should have returned from Volkovo a while ago. Something must have gone wrong. We must go there and find out what happened.
Soviet turncoats are worse than the Fascists.
We found some mushrooms.
They're going to kill me if I refuse to work.
Everything was fine before the partisans showed up.
Don't play dumb with me, captain.
Prevent the reinforcements from being called in
Don't let yourself be found
Don't let yourself be found!
Don't let the enemy reach the river
I never envisioned my life like this!
My life is so miserable...
We didn't fight for this.
Don't forget to distribute your partisans' skill points before sending them on a mission.
You can use tactical pause mode to weigh your decisions without undue haste.
Save your game often. Unless, of course, you chose the highest difficulty level: In that case there are no second chances.
I don't know how much longer I can stand.
Are you from Zorin's group?
Don't use the MG emplacement
I shouldn't have become a Polizei.
We shouldn't have given up.
Please, don't do it!
They'll cut our salaries if we fail to find the prisoners.
Hand drills don't need any electricity to function.
Don't raise the alarm!
I don't want to get shot.
How could this happen?
They aren't Polizei, but they're armed.
Nah, they aren't coming. They're scared.
Joining the Polizei was the right thing to do.
They could burn down the village.
I feel sorry for that family.
Nightmarishly difficult
Don't shoot!
Don't kill me!
They can't get away!
Not enough skill points
Not enough ammo
I wouldn't want to be in their shoes.
They don't respect me, so I have no problem scaring them.
They shouldn't have annoyed the Germans.
He doesn't move.
Small favor
They must be in the forest.
Impossible
Not a week goes by without an execution.
Week
Week: 
Stealth training I
Stealth training II
Stealth training III
Stealth training IV
Eliminate the enemies near the mill
Some items you find during your missions are necessary to completing your assigned tasks. They are marked with an exclamation point in the lower-left corner of the item icon.
Some of your partisans' abilities can be used at a distance. The ability icon shows the exact location where the ability will be used.
There was nothing he could do but share some food.
You cannot send less than {0} partisans to conduct this mission
You cannot delete quest item
German Pamphlet #1
German Pamphlet #2