A little spot of blood? So what?
Nothing serious.
It's just a scratch.
Blowing up a tank in the repair yard isn't much.
Got a death wish? I can help!
Get up! We're in trouble! Punishers are coming to town!
Please, Uncle Grisha! We took a vow! Didn't you say you had a code?
Please leave us be! We had nothing to do with the bridge!
We're going to beat the Germans!
Watch out. After yesterday's attack, the area is far from safe.
You'll go with the soldiers.
They can get in trouble if they go out looking for you.
And while they're evacuating, we have another mission in store...
The authorities are obliged to take extreme measures against these thugs!
We'll teach them a lesson!
Your suspicions seem well founded. My people will look into it.
The Polizei and village heads have all scattered.
The Polizei! They're looking for us! What are we going to do?
Shoulda kept your head down!
How do you like it, huh?
I did it!
Remember: Moscow counts on us!
Here comes the storm!
I know, Valentina Alievna. I'm almost ready to give the shirt off my back myself.
Do you hear me, Fetisov? No shooting until we arrive!
I hear you, Comrade Captain. I'll keep a rein on myself.
Gotcha!
I'm shot!
I hit one!
I've been shot!
Try and dodge this, scum!
Try to operate the semaphore. The controls are in the signal box near the crossing.
I'll try and sneak along the fence while the guards aren't looking.
It's time we put a stop to that before the Fascists turn all the trees in the forest into wooden overcoats.
It's time we did something about Biermeier.
Croaked.
You have a task for me?
I'm back in.
The last laugh is mine!
This is my final warning.
Last time I saw your comrades, they were very much alive. But Zobel was taking them to prison.
We'll see who gets to him first!
Let's see what they have on 'em.
We can give them our protection. Let's head out immediately!
Let's find him first.
Hold on! There's a stash under that floorboard. Take the meds and the gun.
Let's do a head count.
Let's dance!
Hang on in there.
No casualties.
Then we retreat to a safe distance and wait for the train.
Yeah but Doctors are well-respected, and they're always in demand.
'Cos a shell can kill more Fascists than a bullet.
Looks kinda safe.
Accidents like that should happen more often. It’s not much but it’s still a small victory.
Why us, Commissar? We let ourselves get captured in Volkovo, remember?
Why is the truck still empty?
We're almost there. There's light in windows. It means, Biermeier is up.
Beat it!
Following in your father's footsteps?
Let's go, Sanek. Those leaflets won't write themselves.
Have mercy! It's not my fault the road turned to mud!
We'll act under the cover of darkness. It'll make us harder to spot.
This is why I'm here. I need a volunteer to help me get them out of prison.
You wanna say something?
That didn't last long, though...
We'll have to find a key to the fire escape after that. So same difference, I guess.
Praskovya
They have enhanced railroad security, chopped down forest, reinforced patrols...
Stop it you two. You’ll both be peeling potatoes when we're done. But first, we have a job to do.
Cease fire!
Stop bickering! By the laws of war, a traitor must be sentenced to execution by firing squad.
Every crime should be punished.
They resisted arrest and they shot five Polizei dead!
I need to teach you some discipline.
I'll have to switch weapons.
Hey, I know! We can write in broken Russian, like the Fascists.
I'll crush you!
I could show you around! I'll show you everything! The Kremlin, the Arbat, and the Bolshoi Theater!
It's arrived! Bertha is at Krasnoselskaya station!
Keeping 'em down!
All houses along the railroad must be cleared—the Commandant's orders!
I should just kill you and run for dear life!
Hey, cover me.
I wish we could use these on a rifle!
I'll take that as yes, then. Why were you in prison? What for?
It's as if the sky is crying.
Shot the bastard.
We're here! Pops is away hunting. He'll be back in a few days.
We're here. Let's look around and go over the plan once again.
It’s good to know they think we're dangerous.
We'll sneak through the backyards along the riverbank. There's a smaller bridge at the outskirts of the village.
I said, get lost!
Let's move on.
Damn it!
Damn it! I can see smoke ahead.
Damn! My German doesn’t stretch to drunken banter.
I'll tread softly.
We need to infiltrate the farmstead and kill the Commandant. That’ll throw a wrench in the Germans' plans.
I'm sorry. I had no idea. But Zorin and I haven't run, have we?