Cigarettes
Partisan
Partisan throws a knife and silently kills an enemy. Thrown knife can be picked up and used again.
Nikitin takes an enemy as a body shield and can no longer receive damage. Requires a loaded pistol.
They're going to execute partisans.
The partisans are nowhere to be seen.
I can’t see any partisans. They must be lying low.
They're nowhere to be seen. They must be hiding.
Partisan draws attention from enemies, preventing them from attacking allies.
Partisan will begin the mission!
Allows the partisan to deal with medium difficulty missions on the global map.
Allows the partisan to deal with easy difficulty missions on the global map.
Allows the partisan to deal with very hard difficulty missions on the global map.
Allows the partisan to deal with hard difficulty missions on the global map.
Partisan whistles, drawing enemy attention.
Partisan's camp
Partisan School
Partisan detachments are harassing the combined German-Finnish forces occupying several regions of the Karelo-Finnish Republic. The Fascist command sent numerous soldiers to deal with the partisans, reinforced security units guarding the roads, bridges and warehouses, and still the fearless partisans are managing to find weak points and deal heavy blows to the enemy. A small Finnish garrison had set up in the village K. A partisan unit commanded by Comrade L. surrounded the village under the cover of darkness and ambushed the Finns. The partisans killed 20 enemy soldiers, destroyed a warehouse full of supplies and captured two machine guns and several dozen rifles.
A partisan unit organized by the prisoners we freed at the lumber mill successfully blew up the officer's Kübelwagen. Here's to a good start!
Partisan Chest
I hear the partisan commander's name is Zorin. It derives from "the dawn," the morning star.
Partisans 1941
The partisan group appreciates your help. They were able to heal their comrades' wounds, and now they can get back out there and keep fighting.
The Partisans are getting too cocky!
In the meantime, the partisan group was preparing their next operation: a series of railroad sabotages. Collapsed bridges and derailed trains carrying men and supplies would significantly disrupt the enemy's ability to fight a war.
Partisans are going to avenge us.
Character is busy. Saving is not possible.
Partisans don't waste any time, do they?
The partisans attack the Fascists where they least expect it. In the afternoon hours of the 29th of August, a squad led by a former land planner W. eliminated 30 German motorcyclists at the motorway near Toroshkovichi. Partisans had set up an ambush at the clearing by the road. When Germans approached, the partisans let loose several pigs and hens in the clearing; the soldiers, leaving their motorcycles behind, immediately went to chase their prey. Partisans fired several volleys and then rushed the Fascists, killing everyone.
The partisans take no prisoners.
The partisans were exceptionally happy to receive extra supplies.
Partisans will begin their mission! Are you sure?
Partisans don't spare Polizei lives.
The partisans are here!
The partisans won't care why I joined the Polizei.
All they can do is hide away in the woods!
Partisans are vicious!
Partisans here are ruthless. Crazy beasts!
If the partisans kill a single German, the rest of them could burn down the whole village.
Partisans! Shoot them!  
Partisans! Shoot them! 
Partisans! You're our only hope!
Partisans! Oh dear! You've come for help!
Partisans? Phew!
It's cloudy, but there's no precipitation
Ammo and reloading
Pause between shots increased. Movement speed reduced. Stamina reduced. Stealth killing is impossible; must melee instead. 
Beat it, kid.
First aid
First aid I
First aid II
First aid III
My first encounter with the partisans wasn't particularly joyful. They came in the middle of the night and, having found nothing else of value, took my wedding dress. "I'll give that to my Marusja, that'll cheer her up," said one of the bandits.
The first military semi-automatic pistol, adopted in 1934. The TT pistol has simple construction and low production cost, and it's easy to maintain. Its powerful cartridge provides an unusually high penetrating power, but has a reduced stopping effect. This weapon looks worn from battle.
The first military semi-automatic pistol, adopted in 1934. The TT pistol has simple construction and low production cost, and it's easy to maintain. Its powerful cartridge provides an unusually high penetrating power, but has a reduced stopping effect. This is a medium-quality weapon.
The first military semi-automatic pistol, adopted in 1934. The TT pistol has simple construction and low production cost, and it's easy to maintain. Its powerful cartridge provides an unusually high penetrating power, but has a reduced stopping effect. This is a high-quality weapon.
Eliminate the attackers
Get to the other bank
We recommend mastering the game's core mechanics before playing this mode.
Hand over
To hand over
Moving through bushes creates noise that can cause nearby enemies to become suspicious. If your plan was to remain undetected, wait for their suspicion level to decrease before carrying on.
Partisan makes much less noise while moving.
Partisan makes less noise while moving.
To reload weapon
Weapon reloading
Reloading!
Evasion roll I
Roll call
Switch weapons to firearms at the beginning of the battle
Move everything to the storage
Jumping over fences
Transit camp
Your characters can sustain a variety of different injuries, which can have various effects on gameplay. Characters can also be placed into different states. Your partisan Fetisov is in a "Stabilized" state and not able to act.
We don't sing songs any more.
Typewriter
Luger
Pistols I
Pistols II
Pistols III
SMG I
SMG II
SMG III
I haven't received a single letter from my husband since August.
Food:
Operation plan
Artillery plotter
Unlike the kolkhoz administration, the Germans paid on time and liked to point that out. The bread they paid us with, however, often contained sawdust.
They're hunting for partisans in villages.
Several kilometers away from here, a small truck convoy is moving down the road. The composition and the escort remain unidentified.
Several kilometers away from here, a small truck convoy escorted by an armored vehicle is moving down the road. This dangerous mission requires thorough planning.
Several kilometers away from here, a small truck convoy escorted by a motorcade is moving down the road. We should carefully plan an ambush.
Several kilometers away from here, a small truck convoy is moving down the road. We could set up an ambush.
I'm under fire!
Wolves have been howling near the camp at night. We should scare them away before they get too bold.
On Biermeier's orders, Fascist looters (the so-called "procurement teams") are plundering villages. Right now, they're raiding the grain elevator where the entire kolkhoz's harvest is stored. Unless you defend the goods, when the winter comes, the townsfolk will starve. The mission is to eliminate the brigands at the elevator.
There's a cart heading down the forest road. It carries food gathered by the villagers for the commandant. It's not well-guarded, so... should we try to capture it?
There are five manhunts a week! I'm sick to death of it.
The Commandant has ordered villagers from the occupied areas to harvest whatever crops are still left in the fields. Most of the harvest is then sent to the front; the rest is distributed among the local garrisons. The mission is to infiltrate the storage depot and poison the supplies ready for shipment.
Villagers have reported seeing Germans near the mill. This is strange, because usually the Polizei take charge of grain delivery and flour collection. The miller lives there with his daughter. We have to visit the mill and see if they need assistance.