The regional commandant is driving through a communal farm that has been pillaged by the Germans. The Fritzes staying in the workers' homes are planning to give him a warm welcome, and we're gonna make sure it's his last.
The enemy will start receiving reinforcements after a certain period of time.
Сraniocerebral injury
Cherniy woods 
It's empty. Crap!
I hate this runny nose.
Damned Polizei...
Clear blue sky
God damn!!! A corpse!
What's in this container?
I can't believe this is happening!
Another day, another misery.
What's going to happen to us?
What's that?
I hope that hurts!
I don't feel so good...
In order to figure out what the enemy is going to do next, we need to get some documents from the regional comm station. It's under heavy guard, so we need to make sure we're ready for this sortie.
Colonel Mellenberg has dispatched a death squad headed by SS executioners. He wants to punish the townsfolk for their underground activities. You've dealt with the executioners at the front. You know their ways. The townsfolk need your help.
Don't forget to use your character's skills to fulfill their potential.
The Commandant is launching a massive anti-partisan mission, which involves the SS death squad. The only way to disrupt their plans is to eliminate the enemy commanders.
No strangers in sight.
Critical damage chance
Critical chance
The Germans blame us for things we didn't even do!
PMZ sewing machine
The Polizei chief is a real psycho.
Splints can be made even with sticks and rope.
Encryption
They're sneaking around like rats.
Shock
Chocolate
Espionage
Syringe
Stick your bayonets into the ground! Fighting for Stalin, you're fighting for slavery, for the imprisonment of the peoples of the Union!" 
Noise in bushes
Sprint noise
Watch out! 
I'm falling asleep.
It's gonna blow!
Glass of vodka would be nice right now...
I wish I could feel a woman's touch right now.
I could go for some grits with bacon crisps.
It won't hurt.
EQUIPMENT
ENCYCLOPEDIA UPDATED
EFFECTS
Equipped
Equipment.
Item equipment
Expert partisan
"Eiserne Ration" emergency rations. One portion contains:
Grain Elevator
Encyclopedia
This door is locked! I need a key.
This is not going to hurt you.
What the hell's that?
This is our punishment for abandoning God!
I have never betrayed my motherland. The motherland betrayed me!
That's just too much.
Do I have to learn German?
Is this blood?
Effective distance
Effective shooting
Ugh, there's nothing left.
S
I am always prepared on order of the Workers and Peasants Government to rise to the defense of my Motherland, the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; and as a fighting man of the Red Army of Workers and Peasants', I promise to defend it bravely, skillfully, with dignity and honor, sparing neither my blood nor my life itself for the achievement of total victory over our enemies.
I'm hungry as a beast.
I promise conscientiously to study military affairs, in every way to protect state secrets and state property, and to my last breath to be faithful to the people, the Soviet Motherland, and the Workers-Peasants' Government.
I haven't seen anything.
I didn't do anything.
I'm not afraid of the partisans. Let them come.
I'm scared of the Polizei!
I'm the head of the family now.
I live with my uncle.
I heard something.
My feet are blistered because of these boots.
I, a citizen of the Union of the Soviet Socialist Republics, entering into the ranks of the Red Army of the Workers and Peasants', take this oath and solemnly promise to be a honest, brave, disciplined, vigilant fighter, staunchly to protect military and state secrets, and unquestioningly to obey all military regulations and orders of commanders and superiors.
Poison
Language
VO language
Eggs
active
alternative
Belarusian
bio
Melee 
fighter
quick save
 you need to learn more skills
return
return to camp
purchase
take all
rifles
on
military lawyer
rotate - zoom in/out
all
select the Character
select all Characters