So it seems that I wasn't destined to die today. Thank you!
I can see the enemy.
I see you've arrived safely. I was afraid you'll get caught by the Germans along the way.
I saw you coming, so I pulled over. I didn't expect your car to skid!
It looks like a sabotage. Could our hunter have done this?
Careful, there's a mine.
There was an airstrike and people were inside their houses.
First up, there were no other volunteers.
I'd wager they were meant to be part of that counter-partisan operation.
Let's take this baby with us.
Come with us, buddy. We'll find you a better use.
I'll see you get your parole when the war's over.
The place is chock full of Fascists.
If you can't stand the heat, keep clear of the kitchen, right?
Look, there's a couple of them over there. Let's ask them.
That girl was killed over there.
There they are, the vipers.
We'll take 'em by surprise.
You're such a brooder, Nellie! They're not even two hours late, and look at you! You’re already driving everyone mad with your worry!
Would be nice to see them again some day. They may even be defending Moscow now.
I miss the sun.
Think you're tough, bitch?
Listen to that scum! We must shut his pie hole.
No more Fascists left.
As you can see, my childhood dream has come true.
Then do it silently, or you'll only have one eye left to watch from.
I'm afraid the Fascists will take it out on local folk as well. The SS are vicious in their vengeance.
I’m asking myself the same question.
Someday some man is going be lucky to have you as his wife! Or are you already married? Tell me, Valentina Alievna.
I've got some meds.
There's the top dog.
There's our adversary.
That's how you feel, huh? I thought nothing could rattle you and the Sergeant.
So you did, huh?.. In that case, I don't mind you staying here. But make sure you deal with every one of them!
My recon experience comes in handy.
The Red Army will stop the enemy before they reach Moscow—and chase them right back to where they came from!
You dirtbag! You just killed a man for no reason!
You piece of crap!
That's why they never picked me for the recon.
Will you get lost already?
Suppose we win the war. What next? I go serve my time again?
I'm a busy man.
Nothing gets past you, huh?
You little rascal! Turning my words against me, huh?
There we go.
This is my kind of sport!
Here's your new tie.
That's what you get!
Now you’ve made me real mad!
Sanek  told me you had medals from competitions.
I never expected him to become a partisan.
Uh, Shaitan!
Onwards! We'll show 'em hell!
Into battle! It’s time for the enemy to lose it head!
Let's go.
Germans ahead, in numbers. Get ready to battle.
There’ll be many dangerous operations to come. So it's time, I believe, to swear a partisan oath.
Enemy traps all over the place.
The enemy is defeated!
The enemy is smart, but we're smarter.
Don't count your enemies. Just kill them!
We don't have much time, so I'll be brief. This task will be our most challenging so far.
I know these are difficult times, but, come on, can't you cheer up!
Oh no, you don't!
The coast is clear.
Is everyone alright?
All humans are born equal. But you, Hitler's filth, you aren't human.
Is everyone okay?
Alright, we can pass now.
Enough for everyone.
Get down!
I reckon you've had enough?
My trenchcoat looks like a sieve.
My life flashed before my eyes.
The fog is like cold soup.
Everything goes even worse than we expected.
Why don't we knock on his door, see how the old man is doing? He might treat us to something.
I... can't... Too tired...
Whatever we have is in storage. Kulagin will show you around. He's responsible for the supplies.
Pretty much everything we need and in a nice location! Let's take a look.
You got me! Scum!
Your second objective is to hunt down and kill the treacherous village head. He must be somewhere inside the village.
Ta-daaa!
I saw a tank delivered to the repair yard at the crossroad. I thought you might find it interesting.
Yesterday we eliminated the Bogachevo Commandant whose band of thugs had been tormenting the area.
You see Russian soldiers?
You see any strangers?
You’re like a sparrow sitting on a flawless war machine—you don’t really believe you can stop us?
Yeah, you say that, but you haven't tried it.
Are you in charge here? We must hide the grain in the forest.
Do you know some of the resistance fighters? Where can we find them?
Do you know where the enemy are coming from?
Have you been waiting for us?
You didn't tell me about the operation in honor of the Great October Revolution.
You took it heroically! I couldn't have held out like that.
You acted in accordance with the law. That is more than enough for me.
You're approaching the village Pokrovskoye. Your objective is to gain entry to the armory and find the weapons delivery papers.
You once mentioned that justice was above everything else.
You're committing a war crime!
You stay here, guard ze mines!