Keep your eyes peeled.
When does the train leave? How long is it going to stick around?
I can't thank you enough! What they wanted to do was monstrous!
I have no idea. Do you want me to pass the message to the HQ that you're over here?
You’ll get old too... just you wait.
I hate tip-toeing around.
I can't... The wound is too much... Leave me, Sanek. Run. Run for your life before they see you with me.
I hate sneaking around.
Not my day.
We didn't sow it, we didn't reap it, we don't get to eat it.
Not you, commissar. The "diamonds" on your collar.
You're messing with the wrong guy.
They should have kept out of trouble. They gave up their lives for nothing.
It's not very nice.
No!
Please! He's just scared!
Watch your step: there are mines.
Careful, this area is swarming with mines.
I don't like this plan. The breach is too far. I'd rather climb over the gate, find the key, and unlock the entrance for you.
No need to convince me. My mind’s made up. We're staying.
I can't open it.
This is not a unit, this is a madhouse.
We can't afford mistakes.
Not going to happen. Not on our watch!
It... won’t... budge!
Not dying yet, no way.
Why aren't the townfolk putting up a fight?
That's not our ‘intention’. We’re already doing it.
Shouldn't have messed with us!
I won't give up! No one can give up!
Not now. You can do it when I prove myself. All that matters for now is that he's alive.
Don't listen to this bastard! Fascists and their minions are the real enemy!
I don't want to spook them.
Stop fighting!
You should always keep your eyes peeled on duty.
Or went to join the partisans.
Easy now.
They would never. They need me alive. Cornered me like an animal. They know their stuff.
I wouldn't want to be a sapper.
And I'd rather not learn it from the plumes of smoke rising from burning villages. What do you think, Commissar?
I wouldn't want to die on a day like this.
Quiet.
Someone used to live here until last week.
Their time is running out.
We can slip through the breach in the far side of the wall.
We can't afford them to haul the gun to safety at the last moment.
Can you find out if they can get out before the blockade?
We can't just leave this mine behind.
We can't let some local Fuehrer hang it on his wall next to his hunting trophies.
We must go. Headquarters urgently needs the documents.
The Germans took the cattle. And all the chickens too!
The Germans are still here, on guard. Perhaps, they expect someone to try and save the prisoners.
The Germans are scouring the area around the lake. He might still be somewhere close.
They didn't last long.
Nice try.
Competently done.
I lost my eye not far from here.
We'll have our celebration but not right now. There's something bugging me...
It's a difficult mission. I believe they wouldn't have sent just anyone.
Only a few. On the road by the minefield.
Why can't you just stay and command from the back, like normal commanders do?
Nothing to be proud of if you ask me. You'd do well to find yourself a real thing to do.
I'm out of bullets.
No mercy to the traitors and the invaders!
I have nothing left! They took everything! And now they're taking my house!
No, definitely not seen any soldiers.
Ugh, he's not a General! What a shame.
No, this is everyone.
No, from a family of farmers.
No, haven't seen any. Nein.
No, but I was... ninety percent sure you'd show up.
I shouldn't have appeared at the hospital. The Fascists don't care whether you're a Jew or a Kazakh!
Please, stop!
Not really.
Not a damn thing.
I'm out of alcohol! They drank everything!
I can't believe that our people could sell out to the enemy.
Can't see a thing.
Doesn't make any sense.
Never a step back.
They're no longer "our people". Traitors, that's what those Polizei are!
...Nikitin.
I could never imagine him as a partisan contact!
I'll never get used to it.
No, no strangers at all.
You go nowhere. Or it's sein head.
Nicht verstehen. Bitte. Zu essen.
Nothing personal.
It did nothing when the Germans burned down my home and killed my parents!
Child’s play.
These things happen.
It's okay. Stuff happens.
This, too, shall pass.
He'll be fine. I was the same at his age. Nothing but slogans in my head.
We'll pull through.
Nothing.
Killing the SS Commander is even more important.
It sounds like we should wait till morning.
They took his land anyway. That proved too much for his wife.
But that’s what they are themselves! Enemies of the people!