I want it to end.
Quick! Grab the village head before he gets away!
Hurry, we must leave the bombing area!
I can't wait to get back to the warmth.
The Germans will be here soon. We must hold them off until the Commissar has evacuated everyone.
Any minute now. The engine driver is waiting for the signal.
It won't be long, Sanek.
Hold on, kiddo. It won't be long.
Real scorcher today. Makes you sick.
Have you missed me?
Thank god!
A good battle.
Watch it, peasant. I'm easily offended.
We have a plan.
The next morning, the checkpoint got attacked, and when the Germans started to fire, the shells jammed.
He's too big for me!
Got off too easy, if you ask me.
You'll get the words, I wrote them. I’ve done my best to express our shared values.
Serving the Commandant for money. Some are worse than the Germans!
I serve my country.
I serve the Soviet Union.
They already got in trouble... so now I live here with Pops.
Hey, Sanek, what did the Red Army do to you?
Listen up! Two prisoners escaped from the camp today!
Don't hold your breath. He’s been promising me a new pair of boots for quite some time now.
I'm listening
Will be done, Herr Officer!
Did you hear that? Off you go!
I hear the Germans got themselves a valuable trophy: a Division banner!
Hey, boss, what's with the papers in the wagons?
Death to invaders!
Death to the torturers!
Death to the Fascists!
Check this out: the truck didn't stall! It was blown up!
I'll be damned, it worked! Not so many Germans lurking at the station now.
Watch it. The commissar might notice.
Outside, talking to the Polizei. You're going to have to leave.
She's gon' blow!
I'm going to help others first.
Returning to duty.
That look again. Still nagging doubts?
Hit.
I'm fine. But it looks like you took a bullet.
From the checkpoint up the street, where the hospital is.
Damned wretch!
He was going to hunt by the forest lake, where the plane crashed.
Respect my rank!
People these days! Nothing but holes in their pockets.
Agreed. Let's see whether we're any good as saboteurs.
Like I'd mind. A nurse like this is my worst nightmare!
I agree! It will leave him with a taste of impunity and things will turn really ugly.
I'll live.
Their numbers are dwindling!
The sun’s gone cold.
Red sky at night, miller’s delight.
Good thinking.
Keep cool.
My heartfelt condolences. I’m sorry we arrived too late.
We're saved!
Thank you, brothers!
Thank you, comrades! I’d have been tortured to death, that's for sure.
Thank you for saying that.
Thanks a ton!
Thank you! We wouldn’t have lasted long here.
Thanks a ton, Uncle Vasya.
Thanks. I'm trying my best.
Thanks for holding it for me.
Special training in action.
Sleep tight.
Rest in peace, pretty boy!
And the list of female military professions isn't all that long.
Sleeping like a baby.
We face obstacles at every turn!
It's been reduced to rubble. The Germans couldn't take it, our comrades fought back fiercely.
Calm down.
Let's see who kills the most!
He's an athlete. A student at the university of health and sport in Leningrad.
I killed him!
Spare me! It's not about the weapons, it's about skill.
I can, no problem. There are no critical injuries. Good luck to you.
Ah, they're on their guard now!
An air strike is planned on the station. But for that to happen, someone has to disable the anti-aircraft guns.
A station, even small like this one, is a well-guarded strategic object.
This old oak's still going strong!
This old goat’s still got his horns!
An old crow is no fool!
Can't teach an old dog new tricks.
They ordered the village head to build a gallows and he built it high.
Old age hurts more.
Old woman
Chief told me Gavrilych didn't like the Reds much.
An old fox knows the traps.
An old horse knows when to jump.
The old dog bites hard!
Old wood is the best to burn.
Chapter 167.
Is revenge worth behaving as badly as your enemy? And it’d drive the Germans wild. Do you want them to punish the locals?
Stop! There's a present for us here.
Stop! There are mines!
Freeze! It's a landmine.