But he doesn't show his face outside!
But my friends talked me into volunteering together.
The time has come for you to lay down your arms and surrender, or else this lovely young Fräulein will die.
There's only two of us, Captain. What can we do? They drove a whole army backward. We're just like two sticks in a forest!
That's even worse! We must do something! We must get 'em out before it's too late!
But I'm sure that, after Bogachevo, the prison and the comms station, we're capable of handling our next task as well.
But I don't think he was talking about women. That could be vital info.
She's got the prettiest nose in the world! The picture isn't that good.
The communication facility was attacked tonight. The word on the street is that it was the partisans.
Tonight, our air force strafed a truck convoy.
It is that hour when thieves and trappers leave their beds.
How do you like that?
But still?
Of course! Who else? She's new, I want to show her around. Besides, she was attracting too much attention.
Do you have a family, commissar?
Come on, get up!
So where's the army?
There's so much mud.
What a fool!
Well, well, I didn't expect to hear that from a commissar!
This is some weather we're having!
Just look at the prices! Is that what they charge back there, in Europe?
So, who laughs best now, huh?
Is he feeling better?
Please!
So go do their work yourself.
Don't look at me! I'm not walking into their lair again! I haven’t recovered from the last time!
No way. It's your turn.
Are you ready, Fetisov?
So, have you seen the people living under the Fascists?
That was a good start, comrades! It'll take them a while to fix that bridge now.
Anything on him?
Oh, I'll get you for this.
You’ll be jumping with joy, Sanek.
A couple.
Try to be kind to people!
Look, if it turns out that you failed to report them, you'll wish you'd never been born.
Well, well, let's see what's in those pockets.
Well?
We need a doctor!
We need a key.
We need explosives.
Resuscitation needed!
Got to be careful here.
I have to be strong.
We have to disable two AA guns on the platform.
We must examine the crash site and search for survivors.
We need to take the civilians to a safe place. They won't make it on their own — too many patrols on the roads.
This wound needs attention.
We’ll find a safe place and dress your wounds.
We need to get to the mill up the road.
First, we need to kill the guards at the logging area and the boat dock. Then we can damage both head rigs.
We need to have at least a bare minimum.
Need more ammunition!
Need bullets.
About us?
What are you thinking about, commander?
I didn't think of that... We can take him to Mikhailovo, to Uncle Vasya. He won't betray you.
They promised to reopen the church,
This isn't the right way to address an officer!
Oh, you're in trouble now!
Wow! The St. George! What did you get it for?
We're in luck! Let's search the train and find the papers. Can't leave them to the enemy.
Fire!
One of them grabbed me and my father tried to stop him... They shot him dead!
Another one down.
The good thing is that the Germans are just as blind as us.
Wiped out one.
I bagged me one!
Uh oh! That’s a mine!
Eh, I haven’t learned the words yet!
It's all right, it isn't a secret. My parents wanted to marry me off to a man they’d found. And I wanted an education!
Yikes! They can see me!
Damn! A mine! We must defuse it.
Sir, don't hurt me, sir!
Oh, no!
My fault!
Oops, I don't have any more bullets!
Have you fallen for anyone, Olya?
Olya, are you alright? I heard you crying last night.
Olga, what's your specialty? A legal officer?
Where did you learn to shoot, Olga?
Olya, your eyes are red. Are you okay?
He's the Fascists' head executioner! There are rumors about him that'll make your hair stand on end!
I’d get him talking!
It's outside the repair shop. The area is well-guarded.
He wouldn't blow up a convoy, it's too risky.
He left the station early. So he survived the air strike.
That's him. His gang burned down a village recently.
He went that way!
It will mark the anniversary of the Great October Revolution. There are two main objectives.
Did they torture you?
Aren't they going to avenge their own?
They call themselves partisans and claim to be fighting the enemies of the people!
They're going to execute us!
That's us. We want a look at the tank.
They leveled everything! Zobel will pay!
They found out he was a Great War hero and set him free.
Screw me! A mine!
We're dangerously close.