Soltsy
Sort items
A neighbor wants me to join him and become a Polizei.
The village head's buddies noticed that something was wrong. We were forced to leave.
Concussion
Saving
Saving your game is unavailable due to the difficulty settings.
Saving completed
Saved Games
Social
Social ability.
Bipods
Run for your life!
Escape!
Lord, keep us safe.
Thank you for everything you do!
Save the prisoner
I feel sleepy.
Special training
My back aches.
The list of crimes perpetrated by the Fascist blackguards is growing every day. After an unsuccessful attempt to cross the river E., the Germans gathered 50 women and children from the surrounding villages. They put them on the boats and used them as cover while they tried to reach the other bank.
Matches
A bag made from roughly braided strings. Can hold up to 70 kilograms of goods.
Abilities
Allows you to stun enemies of higher rank (Wehrmacht soldiers).
Sprinter
They can't find me if I hide.
Partisan's Companion #1
Partisan's Companion #2
Partisan's Companion #3
Partisan's Companion #4
Partisan's Companion #5
Partisan's Companion #6
Partisan's Companion #7
Partisan's Companion #8
Partisan's Companion #9
Compared
To compare
Medium
 Medium chance of success
Allows you to silently eliminate a careless enemy.
Steel will I
Stamina x 2
Bogachevo station
Krasnoselskaya station
Always seek cover in combat to minimize the damage to your fighters.
Last for as long as you can.
Military award
I buried my husband. I don't want to bury my sons, too.
Staroselskaya swamp
Village head
The village head of Zaborovka is one of the most zealous among the traitors. He works hard to identify the suspicious and the unreliable—especially among the people he has personal quarrels with.
The head of the neighboring village is celebrating his anniversary. It could be his last one. Let's pay him a visit.
Senior technician, Lieutenant Leonid Alexeevich Bykov from the village of Ostrova, in the Sebezh district of the Pskov region.
Sergeant suggests making leaflets detailing the basics of the partisan operations and spreading them among the locals. Sounds like a good idea!
The chief says they took Leningrad.
Stationary machine gun
Glass
Glass canteen
Glass canteens were popular in the Red Army before and during the early stages of the war. Soon, due to aluminum shortages and the blockade of Leningrad (where most aluminum canteens had been produced), glass became even more widespread.
There are too many orphans begging for food in villages.
There's so much death.
The guard Yefim has become a Polizei, and he's running amok. He's more than the villagers can handle! He abuses them and robs them blind. Let's knock him down a peg—or rather, just knock him off.
Strategist
It's damn scary!
I'm scared for my family.
Swiftness
Swiftness I
Swiftness II
Swiftness III
I have a weird feeling.
Kinda creepy.
Building resources
Building resources:
Construction
Construction complete
Slender Bertha
Studenovo
Dry herbs
We collected Avdotya's bread. It's the crispiest and most delicious bread we've ever had!
This is a good stash with a lot of useful items.
Lucky bullet
A lucky large coin with one edge hammered flat and sharpened. He uses it for pick-pocketing.
I'm full, I'm drunk, I don't have to work... just living my dream!
Here!
PARTISAN TACTICS
PARTISAN TACTICS. The main goal of the partisan activities is to eliminate the Fascists' troops and materiel. Success in this struggle depends on the following:
CURRENT SQUAD MORALE
INJURIES
ENEMY CORPSE
TT
Tobacco
Tobacco can block a dog's ability to smell for a short time. The Ministry of Health warns: Smoking kills!
Pills
This strategy gives the partisans enough time to unload the captured supplies from the truck or car. Loud gunfire, on the other hand, may attract the Fascists' attention—and they'll immediately send motorized troops to assist the assaulted convoy.
All right!
Wish I had some milk, but they took the cow.
Their so-called "procurement teams" are nothing but robbers who steal supplies from the locals and leave them to starve. I saw a convoy of their trucks on the way to the grain elevator. We need to stop them.
This is outrageous.
That'll teach them.