The birds are about to migrate, but we still have a chance to hunt. However, we don't want to attract unwanted attention with gunfire.
Machine Gun
Machine guns are highly effective weapons, but they need large amounts of ammunition. 
Lewis
Lewis machine gun
Let them come if they have the guts.
The partisans are to blame.
Just let them set foot here!
Gr-r-r...
SPLIT
DISBAND
CONSUMPTION
FOOD CONSUMPTIONS PER DAY
SHOVEL IN COMBAT
Radio Station
Enemy Radios
If the Germans can do it, we can do it too.
Run!
Divide into groups and look for partisans!
No one can find them now.
Exploration
Scout
Split
Broken arm
Different mechanical items.
UI Scale
Clip size
Place all your characters in the specified area to exit the location.
Take apart
Find the village head
Tendon rupture
Unload
Region available for exploring
Enemy Ranks
Enemy ranks reflect their danger level. To see the rank, hold ALT or hover your mouse pointer over the enemy. 
We should have fought earlier.
We used to beat the Germans, and now they beat us.
We beat them before, we can beat them now!
We found the stash. Gavrilovich helped us return the valuables to their owners, and we got to keep the rest.
Train schedule
Loot spreading
Tripwire mine
Tripwire deals area damage and can be very good for making abushes.
Consumption
large clip size
Revival kit
Revive a partisan
The child got lost in the forest. Let's hope she can make it to safety on her own.
Inspector General
A World War I revolver, converted to 7.62 caliber. This is a single-action model. Low firerate is compensated by high damage and a large stopping effect. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A World War I revolver, converted to 7.62 caliber. This is a single-action model. Low firerate is compensated by high damage and a large stopping effect. This is a medium-quality weapon.
A World War I revolver, converted to 7.62 caliber. This is a single-action model. Low firerate is compensated by high damage and a large stopping effect. This is a high-quality weapon.
Rare
Missions Mode
Window Mode
tactical pause
Stealth mode
Massacre I
Result
Recommended difficulty level for the first playthrough
Railroad war
Out of Commission
Critical for your unit to function. Without food your partisans will starve.
Used for building new weapons and upgrading existing ones. Occasionally required for campaign map events.
Resources found:
Reward: {food} food {grocery} resources.
Reward: {food} food.
Reward: {grocery} resources.
Base resources
Our speech didn't sound very convincing. The townsfolk booted us out.
Decisive battle
We decided not to bother with the stash. We didn't think that the Polizei could have anything of value, and we don't need any wristwatches or earrings.
Slingshot I
Slingshot II
The Motherland Calls!
Shotgun shell
Shotguns I
Shotguns II
Shotguns III
Russian
Hand drill
Hand mixer
Hand mixers are handy for whipping up eggs and making cocktails.
Fishing 
Fish spot
A battle's breaking out! Hide!
The Germans laid a landline along the village border near the woods. We must cut the wires.
N
WIRE AGAINST A MOTORCYCLIST
It's getting worse by the day.
They've got nothing left.
After the Great Patriotic War had broken out, Zoya Kosmodemyanskaya joined the Army as a volunteer in October 1941. She was assigned to a sabotage unit operating around Mozhaysk under orders from Western Front HQ. Twice she was sent behind the enemy lines. During a combat operation in late November 1941, Kosmodemyanskaya was captured in the village of Petrischevo, in the Ruza district of the Moscow region.
One pass can be used by an unlimited number of Red Army and Red Navy officers and soldiers. Stalin's decree ordering reprisals against the families of the deserters is unenforceable. German command does not publish the names of the prisoners, unless they demand this themselves. Do not be intimidated by Stalin's posturing.
Can't get in touch with my family.
Since the first days we've been keeping track of successful operations against enemies. It's time to make this information public—inform the populace of the unit's achievements.
I've been around since early morning.
Horrible rumors have been circulating about the local prison ever since Zobel took over.
I haven't eaten since morning.
This is done.
ASSEMBLE SQUAD