Breakout
A winner takes it all.
We need more of your kind!
Action in battle I
Turn the camera
Damage second gun on the platform
Damage first gun on the platform
Damage the communication facility switchboard
Damage the head rigs
Internal organs injury: Decreased hit chance.
Kidney damage
Killed agents
Let's see what they've got here.
Talk to Trofim
weather
Jumping in front of bullets is stupid.
Suppress fire I
Suppress fire II
Prepare for the attack
Take up defensive positions
Prepare for the arrival of the enemies and eliminate them all.
Agents preparation
Reinforcements incoming!
Reinforcements
We set fire to the construction site. Every little bit helps.
If we blow up the bridge, we can temporarily stop enemy echelons from advancing and delay the arrival of reinforcements, vehicles, and resources. On the front lines, this kind of delay could mean the difference between victory and defeat. Let's help our guys out!
The group of agents appreciate your help. They can fight the enemy now!
Saboteurs discovered that the Nazis were taking trophies to the village of Monastyrskoe and storing them in the church. The brigade banner, which was taken from Fetisov when his company was captured, may be among them. Despite the risk, he wants to enter the building and try to find this banner. It's a matter of honor to take it back.
Object highlight
They blew up a tank, so what? No big deal. It's not a bridge, after all.
I could use a smoke.
The Train Won't Go Any Farther
We burned down the lumber. Every little bit helps.
Allows you to inspire your partisans, increasing their hit chance, firerate and stamina.
Negates injuries until the end of the mission, helping the wounded ignore the pain.
Allows your characters to halt their injuries and ignore their pain until the end of the mission.
Capable of bringing a bucket of water to a boil in 20 minutes... if only you could find some electricity in the woods.
Allows you to ignore effects from light and medium injuries till the end of the mission.
Allows you to ignore effects from light injuries till the end of the mission.
Allows you to notice enemy mines and traps. Time needed to plant mines, tripwires and other explosives is greatly decreased.
Allows you to notice enemy mines and traps. After you detect a mine you can highlight it using ALT. Radius of detection: 700.
A trap to be placed for an enemy. Explodes when someone crosses the wire.
Allows you to distract Polizei and Wermacht soldiers. Enemy will be watching you while talking.
Allows you to distract Polizei. Enemy will be watching you while talking.
Allows you to move near an enemy without drawing enemy attention. Ability stops when you do anything suspicious, such as using weapons or abilities. Cooldown - 10 seconds. Unavailable during combat.
Allows you to climb over high fences.
Allows you to make a short dash to an enemy and deal fatal damage with a knife. Must have a knife to use this ability." 
Allows you to kill low-rank enemies faster when in stealth. Win chance during melee fighting is increased.
Allows you to kill Wehrmacht soldiers and policemen faster when in stealth. Win chance during melee fighting is strongly increased.
Allows you to put every enemy to sleep from behind.
The search
I'd better take it somewhere else.
I'd rather be on my way...
The Fascists will shoot you if they catch you outside at night.
Until They Came...
To leave camp
Leave the village
Leave the town before bombardment
Pokrovskoe v.
Headquarters dugout
Privacy Policy
The Polizei
Members of the Ordnungsdienst and other organizations, colloquially known as the Polizei—turncoats and renegades. The Germans usually arm them with inferior weaponry and send them to maintain order in the villages. Not particularly dangerous.
The Polizei blabbed that the Germans have a stolen red banner at their loot warehouse. We need to get there and get our flag back at any cost.
The Polizei blabbered about a red banner delivered to the German trophy room in Pokrovskoye village. We must go there and reclaim the precious banner.
The Polizei were prepared for an attack. We failed.
The Polizei feel as comfortable as maggots in bacon!
The Polizei are busy raiding a neighboring district. We could tell the townsfolk all about the invaders' crimes.
The Polizei spotted us. We were forced to retreat.
The Polizei are bad.
Polizei
Polizei Yegor, whom we set straight, told us that a supply cart would be crossing through the forest. We could capture the food.
Polizei Petrov, whom we called to civil responsibility, told us about the chief's stash of looted goods. Maybe we should check it out.
A Polizei accidentally told Vasily Gavrilovich that anti-aircraft guns were being positioned around the station in Bogachevo. Some important cargo must be arriving soon.
The Polizei are seeing partisans everywhere.
The Polizei can get away with anything.
Wehrmacht colonel
Recruit every partisan to your cause
Great Diversion
Half rations.<cf>Saboteurs' skills are significantly decreased.
Defensive Position
Half the district is under arrest.
New agent is with you
Item received:
Injured
The supplies you get from looting corpses have become more predictable. For example, you always get the same ammo the enemy was using.
Resources received:
You got what you deserved, you damned Fascist!
Vegetables.
Remember: The forest is your protection. Use trees and roadside ditches as cover against enemy gunfire and for setting up ambushes. Use wattlings and fences to mask your movements. Make gun ports in them, where needed.
Help!
We helped her out. Everyone is happy, healthy, and sated.
We helped her out. She healed the wounded soldier.
Help out
Help Trofim fight off an attack
Help out the hospital personnel
Help 
Help citizens
When I die, who's going to bury me?
We caught several fish.