These items are not stored in the backpack; they are used automatically.
Tactical Pause
Tactical mode
Tactical mode slows time and allows you to coordinate everything your characters do. To activate or deactivate tactical mode, press the SPACEBAR.
I hear gunshots!
We blew up the tank. The Germans can't have it now. We also found some useful items for ourselves.
Tanker
Tarasov
Bloody hell!
Text
Text 
Agent got experience:
Now the main thing is not to step on our own.
We'll live a European life!
I can never wash this off my soul.
The freshly created partisan division had to set up a proper base and find more volunteers to join a losing battle against the invaders. Creating an effective fighting unit was the first order of business.
Now you have a squad of partisans under your control. To select every partisan, press [F1]. To select certain partisans, press numbers [1] to [3].
Now Yegor has a better job to do: deliver useful information to the partisans.
Now we have fresh chicken meat.
Point capture
Capture position
Silent step
Silent move I
Silent move II
I want to live!
I hope we can dodge it...
I hope there won't be gunfire.
Pencil sharpener
We can do this
Decreased hit chance. Increased weapon reload time.
Internal organs injury
Injury is not active until the end of the mission
Injuries
Injuries and states
SMG required.
Rifle required.
Knife required.
Pistol required.
Shotgun required.
Need:
Alerts and Alarms, pt. 1
Alerts and Alarms, pt. 2
Alarm!
Our three people were already bumped off.
Hamstring
Three khutors
Trophies
Trofim
According to Trofim, the Fascists send the PoWs to work at the local sawmill. The treatment is terrible. Trofim suggests we go there, help them escape, and stop lumber production along the way.
Hunting in the dark, Trofim stumbled upon the lair of a bear. He managed to get away, but not without some injuries.
Trofim found a cache with some supplies and canned food, seemingly left here by someone from the local population. Should we take the food, or should we make do without it?
Trofim returns from the forest with the news: The Fascists are forcing the prisoners of war to work on their lumber mills. That's slavery!
Trofim shoots with buckshot, dealing damage to everyone in range of the ability cone. Requires a shotgun.
Serves them right!
Samovar from Tula
The Mutt's dead.
It's a dead body!
mission failure reason
This is dangerous.
I hate this place. I wanna live in the forest, too!
You're Gonna Go Far, Kid
Thousands of Soviet soldiers were surrounded, trapped in salients. One of them was a commanding officer of a rifle company, Captain Zorin. During an attempt to break out of the encirclement, he was taken prisoner and shipped to the nearest Dulag (Durchgangslager — German concentration camp).
Phew, it's water.
Difficult
Heavy weapon I
Heavy weapon II
Heavy weapon III
Life under the Fascists is hard...
Biermeier's got a hot girlfriend.
Biermeier's suit is falling apart!
Mellenberg's got a scarred mug.
You have unsaved changes. Do you want to apply them?
You have no fighters left.
Your characters have very high morale. Hit chance is increased. Character can sprint longer. Ability cooldowns are decreased by 1.5 times.
Your characters have very high morale. Hit chance is greatly increased. Character can sprint longer. Ability cooldowns are decreased by 2 times.
Uncle Fedor has a potato patch by the hill. He once hid from the Soviet rule; now he's waiting the Fascists out. Let's ask him to share some food. 
The captain had to make a choice: attempt to cross the front line to rejoin his comrades, or remain behind the German lines and organize a partisan group. The dire situation in the occupied areas lead Zorin to stay.
Commandant Mellenberg's got some taste. He set up his HQ in an old royal manor home.
I have a toothache.
I don't have the item I need.
The Polizei chief makes my skin crawl.
Here is the courpse! Alarm!
They don't have the guts to attack.
Different weapons are effective at different ranges. To reach maximum efficiency you may need to get closer to your enemy and use cover to decrease the chance of being hit during combat.
My neighbor's kid went missing.
The Fascists are shaking in their boots when they hear about partisans.
TO REMOVE FROM THE SQUAD
DELETE
ENEMIES KILLED
SUCCESS!
REMOVE:
We persuaded Petrov that there are other ways to earn a woman's affection. And that he should deliver information to the partisans, too.
I'm getting killed!
Stealth killing
Kill 100 enemies
Kill 2 enemies during a single use of Fan fire skill
Kill the two Polizeis
Kill 3 enemies using environmetal objects
Kill 3 enemies during a single use of Long burst skill
Kill 3 enemies during a single use of Buckshot skill