Much harder to hit the target
Much harder to hit the target, enemy vision is worse
Difficulty:
Broken arm.
Broken weapon
Broken weapons can be taken apart.
Gear slot
You can cook food using provisions obtained during your missions.
News from the front lines
I hear Zobel tortures the prisoners in person.
We've heard about you. You're doing a great job.
Craft the grenade
Intelligence
Intelligence I
Intelligence II
Intelligence III
Death to the Oppressor!
Fascists' death has come.
Betrayers Should be Dead
The hand of death reaches toward you! Think about your family! Surrender now!
A mixture of gasoline and kerosene in an elegant glass bottle. Burn before usage.
Smolensk has been captured by the enemy, despite desperate resistance of our armies. Hitler's hordes are beginning their rush for Moscow.
The bitches just fled!
Sniper
Equipment 
You can equip your soldiers at the warehouse. Keep in mind that each item you select has a certain cost, and you have a limited number of warehouse points.
You need to equip your team for each mission by spending warehouse points.
At first the Germans weren't particularly cruel. They hired us for odd jobs. I was sent with some other villagers to dig anti-tank ditches. A German soldier was sent to guard us, but we ended up guarding him. He explained to us that he didn't care whether we worked or not; he had never wanted to go to war and had family waiting for him back home. So we had to do our best to keep the Germans from replacing him with someone more strict.
Partisans are always followed by death squads.
Back into battle
They came to rob us again.
They're trashing the house again.
They're going to make us watch the execution again.
Sleeping pill
I wouldn’t quarrel with me if I were you.
Dog
They should die like pigs.
Dogs
Enemy dogs can detect your partisans in the bushes or in other cover; if it comes to combat, they will instantly attack. Sources of strong smells, like tobacco, can throw the dogs off your trail. 
Get together and fight!
Gathering
We found a sack of good root crops and veggies.
We found some slightly rotten root crops and veggies.
We gathered some berries.
We picked several baskets of berries.
We gathered the eggs.
We'll pickle the mushrooms.
Collect honey from every hive at the apiary
Assemble squad
Obtain intact explosives
Gather eggs.
Collect/defuse every mine in the fields
Activity done
Activity failed
Events
Perform 10 rolls
Can't survive on a clear conscience alone!
A clear conscience can't feed you when you're starving!
A Soviet automatic rifle created by S. Simonov and adopted in 1936. It has a very high firerate and a burst mode that can be used in emergency situations. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A Soviet automatic rifle created by S. Simonov and adopted in 1936. It has a very high firerate and a burst mode that can be used in emergency situations. This is a medium-quality weapon.
A Soviet automatic rifle created by S. Simonov and adopted in 1936. It has a very high firerate and a burst mode that can be used in emergency situations. This is a high-quality weapon.
Soviet Pamphlet #1
Soviet Pamphlet #2
Soviet Pamphlet #3
A Soviet internal magazine-fed military rifle. It was adopted in 1891. The rifle has repeatedly proven its effectiveness and reliability in the most extreme conditions. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A Soviet internal magazine-fed military rifle. It was adopted in 1891. The rifle has repeatedly proven its effectiveness and reliability in the most extreme conditions. This is a medium-quality weapon.
A Soviet internal magazine-fed military rifle. It was adopted in 1891. The rifle has repeatedly proven its effectiveness and reliability in the most extreme conditions. This is a high-quality weapon.
Soviet defensive grenade.
Soviet rifle bullet. Suitable for: Mosin rifle, Lewis machine gun, AVS – 36, DP – 27.
A Soviet submachine gun designed by G. Shpagin. It was adopted in December of 1940. High firerate, high consumption of ammunition and rapid overheating of the barrel—the necessary price for a high density of fire. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A Soviet submachine gun designed by G. Shpagin. It was adopted in December of 1940. High firerate, high consumption of ammunition and rapid overheating of the barrel—the necessary price for a high density of fire. This is a medium-quality weapon.
A Soviet submachine gun designed by G. Shpagin. It was adopted in December of 1940. High firerate, high consumption of ammunition and rapid overheating of the barrel—the necessary price for a high density of fire. This is a high-quality weapon.
Soviet pistol ammo. Suitable for: Nagant, TT, PPSh – 41.
A Soviet light machine gun. It was adopted in 1928 and used primarily as an infantry fire support weapon. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A Soviet light machine gun. It was adopted in 1928 and used primarily as an infantry fire support weapon. This is a medium-quality weapon.
A Soviet light machine gun. It was adopted in 1928 and used primarily as an infantry fire support weapon. This is a high-quality weapon.
A Soviet double-barreled shotgun. "Solid, comfortable, reasonably built gun with a reliable curtain, good locks, a strong profile of barrels and a beautiful shape of the lodge." - S.A. Buturlin. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A Soviet double-barreled shotgun. "Solid, comfortable, reasonably built gun with a reliable curtain, good locks, a strong profile of barrels and a beautiful shape of the lodge." - S.A. Buturlin. This is a medium-quality weapon.
A Soviet double-barreled shotgun. "Solid, comfortable, reasonably built gun with a reliable curtain, good locks, a strong profile of barrels and a beautiful shape of the lodge." - S.A. Buturlin. This is a high-quality weapon.
A Soviet single-barrel external rifle developed in 1924. It is modified from the American "Iver Johnson" model. This weapon looks worn from battle.
A Soviet single-barrel external rifle developed in 1924. It is modified from the American "Iver Johnson" model. This is a high-quality weapon.
A Soviet single-barrel external rifle developed in 1924. It is modified from the American "Iver Johnson" model. This is a medium-quality weapon.
The Soviet Government and its head, Comrade Stalin, have authorized me to make the following statement: Today at 4 o'clock AM, without any claims having been presented to the Soviet Union, without a declaration of war, German troops attacked our country, attacked our borders at many points and bombed from their airplanes our cities Zhitomir, Kiev, Sevastopol, Kaunas and some others, killing and wounding over two-hundred persons. There were also enemy air raids and artillery shelling from Romanian and Finnish territory...
The contents of the bottle may be interesting to enemies.
Has anything you'd need to help a wounded fighter. Recovers a huge amount of HP.
Contains everything a wounded soldier needs to become combat-ready again. Restores a large amount of health.
Crafting a trap
Crafting a makeshift grenade
Crafting a makeshift mine
Crafting a medical bag
Craft "Painkillers"
Reduce weapon reload time by 15%.
Decreased ability cooldown.
Decreased ability cooldown. Increased number of ability uses during mission.
Using environment II
Hiding corpses II
Soldier
The war goes on even when the soldier is asleep.
A soldier's talisman. A bullet from the first clip, which is supposed to be shot right after the soldier returns from the war.
Wehrmacht Soldiers