It's easy to catch a cold in the forest in autumn, but medicine is hard to come by. We need to find some medicinal herbs.
Stewed sturgeon
Weaker partisans.
Looting corpses
Reach the medical dugout
Reach the store
Reach the headquarters
I'll look around.
Resource +100
Special control areas
Special conditions
We smoked the rest of it for later.
We'll smoke what's left and store it for later.
Spice It Up
The disease took the lives of many. The village is almost empty now.
From the hospital door
Many locals starved to death. The survivors left for the town.
From each according to his ability, to each according to his needs, hehe.
Can't hide from us.
The partisans are causing enough damage!
A brave artillery officer, who had already distinguished himself along with his division during earlier engagements, chose good positions for his guns. As soon as enemy tanks showed up, the guns opened fire; Captain Khigrin's gun was particularly successful in battering the enemy. Fascist tanks went up in flames one by one, yet still the enemy pressed on, ignoring the losses. All crew members perished under enemy fire. Captain Khigrin assumed the role of a gunner and personally destroyed four enemy tanks; he kept firing until a fragment of an enemy shell cut him down. The enemy advance was halted.
Diversionary Tactics
Distraction I
Distraction II
To start action (set up sequence of actions in tactical pause)
I need a rest.
Calibrated aiming mechanism
Off
Unlocks facility tasks for obtaining food.
Unlocks facility task for obtaining construction supplies.
Unlocks hunting-related facility actions.
Unlocks fishing-related facility tasks.
New region explored
Open all cells with prisoners
Open the camp menu
Great button
Great place for a tripwire.
To cancel action
Reset the partisans' current task.
Show FPS count
Show hit chance in percents
Avenge us!
GO TO ACTIVITY
Send out the train with the Germans
Poison the provisions heading out to the front lines during the farm mission
Poison food rations
Repel all attacks
Repel enemy attacks without using mines or tripwires
A partisan group in the neighboring area is in a dangerous situation. Several members are severely wounded. They ask you to share some supplies.
Officer 
Officer  
Gestapo officer 
SD officer 
Officers can make a roll call and raise the alarm if one of the soldiers is not on his watch.
No enemy officers found
For God's sake!
Ugh!
This can't be good.
Ugh! My back!
Where does this end?
Hunting
Hunter
Hunting Tower
The guards are watching.
The guards missed it! Why is it our problem?
The guards missed it! Why does it have to be our problem?
We killed the guards and set the prisoners free.
Very easy
Very low morale
Warning: high danger!
Very tasty.
Greatly increased chance to hit during ambush mode [Y].
Very hard
Skill points
PARTISANS
FIRST STRIKE
CHANGE INVENTORY VIEW
TO START UPGRADE PUT WEAPON IN WEAPON TABLE SLOT
IT'S TOO FAR AWAY
CHARACTER IS BUSY
RMB - cancel action (cancel entire sequence of actions in tactical pause)
RMB on enemy - see visibility cone
FALLEN FIGHTERS
ACTS OF VALOR
DETAIL
HINTS
VALIDATE
LEAVE MISSION
FULLSCREEN
PPS
PPSh – 41
INCOME
FOOD INCOME PER DAY
CONTINUAR
ORIGIN
ACCIDENT
SKIP ALL (SPACEBAR)
EMPTY
Pavel
Perhaps shooting someone could cheer me up?